Hey everyone, this is Venkata Pagadala. Today is October 1st, 12.55 AM. So today I want to talk about Costco earnings calls and the elements of AI search.
And in brightonSEO 2026 in San Diego, I was talking about the importance of collecting data from different demand sources. Again, this is like 20 demand sources, but I'm expanding those sources and I'm going to show,
surely share more details on that. But for now, I was mentioning earnings calls here, as you can see in a deck. And earnings calls,
I extended a topic in a previous article that's saying that earnings calls connect customers' needs to business profits, where you can talk about investments, customer experiences, and compare those to priority.
So pretty much explaining of importance of earnings calls. So I am extremely happy today to see that Costco CFO, subject to correction, CFO is mentioning about the traffic to Costco from AI search grew triple digits.
It's like AI search triple digits for second quarter in a row, and it converts better than other sources of traffic. Again, whoever is working on organic traffic, SEO, AEO, GEO, whatever call, this tells that users are using AI, not only for research, but actually making conversions.
And this is cited by Costco, which is like, which produced 93.9 billion of net sales, which is up 11.2%. Again, this is like numbers are subjected to little correction there.
So CFO, as you guys know, like it's Gary, so you can read a couple of stats from here, what Gary spoke about. And then sales, that stat in AI tools also grow triple digits.
So this is also really, really great points that we and organic marketers or researchers or AIs, SEO, GEOs need to take this to our leaderships and explain that the importance of AI in the relevance of not only traffic in the relevance of conversions.
So Costco does not pay for digital advertisement. So the CFO sees AI as a neutral place where its value can show up on its own merits.
And digital enabled comparable sales rose like 19.5%. Again, this is like a comparison, like digital, digital enabled comparable sales were up 19.5%. So what did Costco say about AI search?
And I'm not going to read everything, guys. So this is pretty much what they said. And I wrote something about it in the commerce as well. And then I want to specifically talk about one thing here, like, yeah, what did, like, you guys can have like financial numbers, everything here.
What did Costco cover on this call? Like warehouse, it's open 12, it opened 12 in Q4. Again, this is good. But if you see, they're planning to, to open Q4, 10 of them in new buildings, 28 of new stores in 2026.
So they mentioned all these things. So again, this is going to affect local other warehouses.
So it's always good to know what's coming, what's planning, and also they are including four in Europe as well. It's not everything in US. But this is always good to know what's coming ahead.
So it would be great. If you see Costco plans 33 openings in fiscal 2027. Okay, this is where I want to emphasize like, where we needed data intelligence layers is to tell us what's coming.
For example, if 33 are opening, if you see, there will be a market share split in these locations, it can impact directly or indirectly the possible real estate as well. It can impact the gas stations as well.
Talking about the gas stations and pharmacy. If you see a gas, a record year, the share, the share of US member household buying gas reached an all-time high. Costco estimated it saved $3.2 billion.
So, again, it's going to impact the gas stations pharmaceuticals travels and like merchandise like the Costco sales and number of things, and it can impact the local businesses around that as well.
So this is the reason why we need to read and study about earnings calls in the relevance of what we're doing as an AI researchers, or SEO, GEO, SEO, AEO, whatever we call, basically, it's always good to analyze the different data sources in order to understand what's coming and be prepared.
And we need to be well knowledge regarding the business because ultimately our job is to impact the business growth, either in the levels of revenue or traffic or visibility whatever it is, but you need to understand what's coming, what's impacting directly and indirectly.
So, to wrap it up I'm going to share these links and everything on LinkedIn. So, once again, I'm so happy to see in the statements coming from directly a CFO of a Costco so thank you guys.